Everywhere you go in China today, you
see a country in a hurry.
There's a headlong rush to build roads,
factories,
airports,
and tower blocks, entire cities
>> [music]
>> in record time.
>> China's industrial revolution is the
biggest and the fastest in history.
Chinese exports are in every country in
the world, and Chinese companies like
this one are investing literally all
around the globe.
>> You might think the ascent of China
isn't your problem.
But the fact is, we are living through a
massive historical shift of economic and
political power from west to east.
And it's going to affect all our lives.
>> Today, our future and China's are
intertwined in ways that would have been
unimaginable even 10 years ago.
When property prices crashed in the UK,
this place, Canary Wharf, had to be
bailed out by the Chinese.
They're no longer just a source of cheap
imports for us. We need to increase our
exports to them to get our economy out
of the doldrums. Our politicians want
the Chinese to invest in modernizing our
crumbling infrastructure. We need them.
>> And that has implications for us
that are less than palatable.
If China can impose low wages and a
tougher work ethic in emerging markets,
>> The Chinese, yeah, they're telling that
the Western
>> how long before they could start doing
it to us?
Where once we had the [music] bright
ideas and the Chinese just assembled the
components.
>> I have to admit that is pretty cool.
>> Could it soon be the other way around?
>> So the idea that China doesn't innovate
is just completely wrong.
>> That's wrong. I I disagree.
>> When China challenges our most deeply
held beliefs about freedom of speech
locking up outspoken citizens.
Will we soon have to bite our tongues
for fear of losing much needed
investment?
For some Western commentators
>> [music]
>> the prospect of China ruling the world
is already a seriously scary one.
But is the alternative scenario any
better?
Some say that sooner or later this vast
country [music] will collapse into
turmoil.
As so often in the past.
The trouble is a China crash today would
be [music] a death blow to hopes of
economic recovery in the West.
>> [music]
>> And it might also stoke the already
smoldering fire
of Chinese nationalism.
SO WHAT SHOULD WE BE MORE WORRIED ABOUT?
A China that succeeds and takes over the
world or a China that fails and takes
the rest of the world down with it?
We've never seen anything like it.
40 years ago China's economy was smaller
than Britain's.
Today, it's more than six times larger.
In 2016, according to the International
Monetary Fund, it'll probably overtake
the United States
to become the biggest in the world.
To get an idea of just how much China
has changed, take a look at this.
There was a time when these were
something of a delicacy in this part of
the world, but now look.
This is a dog beauty salon, deep in the
heart of Chongqing.
How old is he, or is it a she?
Male.
Wow.
Thank you very much indeed, Rakuen.
You are the new symbol of the new China.
Poodle ownership really is a sure sign
that China has entered the economic
executive club.
Now, on one level, that's good news for
us.
Much of the money the Chinese new rich
spend is going on our luxury branded
goods.
But what I want to find out is if
China's high-speed growth is actually
sustainable.
After all, remember how the American
dream went pop back in 2008?
A collapsing property bubble nearly
brought down the Western financial
system.
You think the Chinese might have learned
lessons from this?
>> But everywhere I go in China, I see this
scene, residential real estate being
built on a vast scale with borrowed
money. I begin to ask myself, is this
just the latest bubble about to burst?
>> And that's not the only threat to
China's miracle economy.
In the space of a generation, the
country's gone from being one of the
most equal societies in the world
to American levels of income inequality.
Every year in China, there are tens of
thousands of protests by the rural poor
who've had their land grabbed by corrupt
officials and rapacious land
speculators.
In the cities, too, there's growing
unrest among China's 250 million migrant
workers.
While a lucky few have become
billionaires,
most have to live on miserable wages
and in shocking working conditions.
The economist Wang Hui is an expert on
the social problems of China's uprooted
masses.
>> We're standing on the outskirts of
Beijing, well, in what was once a
village quite some distance from
Beijing, and there's a lot of
construction going on behind us.
Probably most of the workers on this
site are from very far
from Beijing. These are migrant workers,
right?
>> Yes, migrant workers.
The crucial issue is that the we created
uh 18 million
jobs every year now.
However, every year you have more than
25 million come to the labor market. So,
you always cannot match that the labor.
So, you have to some surplus. So, you
have lot lot people are employment.
>> Which sounds pretty unsustainable to me.
You can imagine a pretty ugly scenario
if the economy here cools off.
Mass unemployment?
Millions of unhappy workers crammed into
cities?
Mounting anger among the rural poor?
This is the fear that has haunted
China's leaders from the time of the
first emperor more than 2,000 years ago.
The fear is that protest could turn into
rebellion.
The obvious way to keep a lid on popular
unrest is more economic growth.
The problem is that there are strong
headwinds threatening to slow that
growth down.
>> [singing and music]
>> It's rather hard to see these wonderful
old people taking their morning exercise
here in Chongqing's Shapingba Park as
part of anybody's problem.
But they are.
Between now and 2050, the number of over
60s in China is going to rise by a
staggering 230
million.
>> So, the share of the elderly in the
population will rise from just 12% now
to very nearly a third. Just as in
Europe, a dwindling number of workers is
going to be supporting an ever larger
population of old folks.
>> And that's not the only threat to
China's continued growth.
Down here, I can literally smell one of
the other huge challenges facing China
today.
>> [music]
>> All that record-breaking economic
[music] growth is causing an
environmental disaster.
>> [music]
>> Cleaning up this mess is going to
require massive investment in green
technology.
>> The scary thing for China's leaders is
that economic success has generated a
whole new set of problems.
And even scarier thing is that sooner or
later, that economic growth is bound to
slow.
China's leaders know they have to
maintain a growth rate of at least 7% a
year just to keep the employment rate
where it is now.
And that means they're being forced to
do something that we in the West may
find more than embarrassingly familiar.
Overseas expansion.
Some say it's the only way to secure the
resources that are needed to keep the
Chinese economic miracle going.
Watching China's expansion in action
provides some fascinating and disturbing
clues about how a Chinese-dominated
world
might look.
>> So,
this factory produces copper piping?
>> Yes, copper tubing.
>> Yeah.
>> Copper piping.
>> Mr. Sun manages this factory for China's
biggest copper pipe manufacturer.
[music]
Actually, the biggest copper pipe
manufacturer in the world.
How much of this stuff does the company
get through?
>> What to say?
Uh 40 uh 400 uh 500 million
>> Or 400,000 tons?
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, 400,000 tons.
>> That is a heck of a lot of copper.
In fact, China now accounts for more
than 2/5 of all global consumption of
coal, aluminum, zinc,
and copper.
The only way to satisfy this insatiable
demand, to keep the Chinese economy
growing, and to stave off unrest at
home, is to seek out those resources
abroad.
And that's why, to understand China's
impact on the world, you really do need
to follow the metal.
This is Zambia.
>> [crying]
>> If you want to get a glimpse of what
it's like to live with Chinese
expansion, it's one of the best places
to start.
For what the Chinese are doing here in
Africa today, they may be doing much
closer to home tomorrow.
>> This mine shaft with its maze of
connecting tunnels has been sunk a mile
down into the heart of one of Africa's
greatest deposits of natural wealth.
It's hot, it's smelly, it's airless,
it's very very noisy, and if you suffer
from claustrophobia, it's hell on earth
or rather hell under the earth about a
mile under the earth to be precise.
But every time you use an electrical
appliance, just turn on the light or
boot up your computer, you're using the
stuff that they mine down here. I'm
talking about copper.
And of course, it's the Chinese more
than anyone who need this copper to
supply their factories
and keep their people working.
This mine in Luanshya is owned by the
Chinese state, which acquired it at a
knockdown price in the middle of the
2009 recession.
Just like the Western economies today,
the Zambians needed the money.
As copper prices surged, driven above
all by soaring Chinese demand,
it proved to be a pretty good
investment.
Mr. Chung and his assistant Jack Liu
typify a new breed of Chinese
entrepreneur.
They've been attracted to Zambia's
copper belt by the promise of juicy
returns,
provided they're prepared to work hard,
very hard.
>> So it works 24/7, 24 hours a day, 7
days.
>> When the machines are in operation
>> Yeah.
>> they work 24 hours.
>> Wow.
And all the copper from here goes to
China?
>> Yes, to China.
>> You created this from nothing. This
wasn't here before.
How many Zambians do you employ now?
How much copper do you produce every
year?
>> 2,000 to 3,000 tons.
>> Tons a year.
You don't need to be a mathematical
genius to work that one out.
>> [music]
>> If you can produce 2,000 tons of copper
a year, and copper costs $8,000 a ton,
then you're grossing $16 million a year.
And that's just in the first year of
this smelter has been operating.
The Zambian Copperbelt [music]
is China's version of the Wild West
these days.
From Ndola to Kitwe, copper kings like
Mr. Chung are getting rich [music]
quick.
And it's not just Zambia,
nor for that matter just Africa.
All over the world, from Angola to
Brazil, all the way to Cambodia, you'll
encounter Chinese managers, engineers,
and foremen
hard at it.
At the very least, China is building a
global portfolio of investments.
At the most, this is the beginning
of a new world empire.
Because this is more than just a
scramble for resources.
The Chinese aren't just coming to Africa
to work.
Some are coming here to live.
>> Okay, let's get serious.
>> Take this man.
>> [laughter]
>> MR. SONG RUNS A SOYBEAN farm a couple of
hours outside Zambia's capital, Lusaka.
He represents the old-fashioned type of
settler, carving a new life out of the
soil.
>> [music]
>> This is a farm that is owned by you or
by a Chinese state company? Who's the
real owner?
>> Oh, the owner? The Chinese state. Okay.
>> So you work
>> I
For me, I'm only manager.
>> You're the manager of the farm. Okay.
>> I wish
I was
owner.
>> Maybe one day you will be.
>> Mm, maybe.
>> How long do you think you will stay here
in Zambia?
>> Maybe forever.
>> Maybe forever?
>> Yes. I like here.
>> You like it here?
>> Yes.
I know.
>> Most of the Chinese I've met in Zambia
are men who've left their families back
home in China.
>> [clears throat]
>> But Mr. Song is so committed to his
future in Africa that he's brought his
wife and daughter to live here, too.
Do you think of yourself
as Chinese or Zambian?
>> It's a big question, eh?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
Zambian.
>> Zambian?
>> Zambian.
>> Great.
>> Surprising.
>> [laughter]
>> But I'm happy with that.
>> That is a good That's a good answer.
>> Yeah.
>> Now we're going to test
the luck. I must say, I can't resist Mr.
Song and his family. Well, he's got the
work ethic all right, but he's got
something else, and something beyond
just a sense of adventure, too.
Something has taken Mr. Song all the way
across the world from China to Africa
and persuaded him to stay.
Funny.
When I look at the Chinese in Zambia
today,
it seems strangely reminiscent of a time
when another global power dominated the
country.
A hundred years ago, it was we British
who owned the copper mines in Luanshya.
When we colonized the place, we came to
stay.
>> The townships have all the amenities,
even if sometimes only in miniature, of
20th century civilization.
>> This is the kind of empire I can relate
to.
It's the uh recreation area.
This was where the officials and
engineers
of the mining company would come
to disport themselves in a very British
way.
>> Like the other recreation club, Roan
Antelope Club, among its many
attractions, has a first-rate bowling
green.
>> And this
used to be the ballroom,
where on Saturday nights
people would come for
drinks and dancing.
Well, it's been converted by its new
Chinese owners
into badminton courts.
How are the mighty fallen.
So, are the Chinese just taking over
where the British left off?
Are their mining investments and their
casinos just the first phase of a secret
plan to build an empire?
Officially, the answer is no.
The Chinese are communists, not
imperialists. They're here in Africa
only to promote mutual well-being.
China gets the copper.
In return,
the Zambians get goodies like this.
This Chinese-designed soccer stadium
could rival any in the world.
It's being built outside Ndola, in
Zambia's copper belt, as a gift from the
People's Republic of China to the
football-crazy Zambians.
Like so much else the Chinese are doing
in Zambia, this is a project that
generates jobs for Africans.
>> How many people will this hold when it's
finished? How many spectators?
>> mean the the capacity?
>> Yeah.
>> It's 40,100
seats here.
>> 40,100?
>> seats. Yes, sir.
After this stadium has been finished, we
made some contribution to the Zambian
government as well as the local economy.
>> So, it's an economic contribution, but
it's also a symbol, isn't it? It
symbolizes Zambian-Chinese
friendship.
>> Yes, correct. Yeah.
>> Do you think a Chinese team will come
here and play a Zambian team?
>> Ah, yeah, maybe.
>> I wonder who will win.
>> Okay, thank you.
>> Who do you think will win? I think
China.
I think China deserves to win. They
built the stadium.
What is amazing about this stadium is
that the local team that plays here
attracts a crowd of 5,000 for its games
normally. So,
I think they're going to feel quite lost
in there when they start playing
regularly.
>> It starts to sound like one of those
win-win propositions they like to talk
about in business school.
China secures its own economic stability
by buying up raw materials
while countries like Zambia get
productive investment instead of the aid
handouts the West has been offering
since the end of empire.
If that's right, then maybe a world
dominated by the Chinese won't be so bad
after all.
But then again,
that's what all empires say.
Win-win.
China invests abroad to secure raw
materials to keep its economy growing
and to head off any unrest at home.
In East Africa, for instance, the
Chinese get the copper their industry
needs so much of.
In return, the people who live here get
jobs
and Chinese construction.
Like this new hospital in the Zambian
capital, Lusaka.
>> Should we go down here?
>> Yeah.
>> There are thousands of Chinese working
on projects like this all around the
world. And boy, do they work.
If you wonder why the manager, Liu Chong
Hong, is looking a bit worn out, well,
so would you if you had his job.
So, how long have you been working here?
>> Me, 20 months.
>> 20 months?
>> Yeah.
>> And in all of that time, have you been
working just on this site, or have you
had any time off?
>> Uh only the Chinese New Year.
>> Only the Chinese New Year?
So, how many days 1 day? 2 days?
>> Uh 3 days.
>> 3 days off in 20 months?
>> Yeah.
>> That sounds like slavery to me.
>> [laughter]
>> There's no time here for pink gins on
the veranda, like in Britain's imperial
heyday.
The Chinese are here only to work.
They just don't have time for anything
else.
When you finish work [music] after 9
hours, do you stay here, or do you go
out?
>> Uh we stay inside the camp.
>> Never go out?
>> I
we go out.
Shopping sometime.
>> Yeah.
Do you go out to bars and drink some
beer?
>> Bars, no.
>> No, we we drink inside.
It's a work ethic that the rest of us
haven't had for a generation.
If you want to know why the Chinese are
catching up with the West, this has to
be part of the answer.
But there's another, less pleasant ethic
you encounter here.
An attitude of superiority over the
locals that's distinctly colonial.
How do the Zambians compare with Chinese
workers?
>> They are not as good as Chinese.
>> Really?
>> That is
>> Yeah.
Jack should know something about hard
labor.
He's been working for Mr. Chong 7 days a
week for 13 months.
He's had 1 day off,
but that was because he had
>> malaria.
What's the biggest difference between
China
and Africa, do you think?
>> I think people.
>> Yeah. What's
>> Cuz we work so hard.
>> Yeah.
>> But them,
not really.
>> Can Africans work as hard as as the
Chinese? Can you Can you train the guys
out there to work as hard as you?
>> Tough job.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz uh it's nature.
Like uh us, we
we tend to be work hard and
>> Yeah.
>> but then
they like enjoy life.
>> Yeah.
>> Not like us.
>> [laughter]
>> I can't help feeling that maybe there's
a lesson here in Zambia for all of us.
As the Chinese come to dominate the
global economy, they'll expect everyone
to work as hard as they do.
And it's not just about the amount of
work.
It's also about the conditions.
The Chinese bought the copper mine here
in Chambishi after it had been closed
for 13 years.
There were no jobs back then.
But now the mine employs more than 1,200
men.
You'd think the workers here would be
grateful.
But they're not.
I guess everybody knows you here.
>> Yes, they do.
>> Agnes Ngandwe is their union leader.
So this is where the miners come on a
Sunday?
>> Yes. Yes.
>> How many days a week do you work?
>> Our system days. Six days.
>> Yes.
>> How well is a miner paid?
>> Relax, cheaper local currency.
>> Really?
>> I was getting 436,000
kwacha. If you get um
500 dollars.
>> Yeah.
>> This sucks us.
>> Oh, I see.
>> All these men are clearly very angry
about the way the Chinese, compared with
other foreign mine owners, treat the
Zambian employees.
>> You work for all these different people.
Who are the worst employers?
>> The worst The worst team are the
Chinese.
>> The worst are the Chinese?
>> The Chinese. The Chinese are the worst.
>> The Chinese may be building a fancy
football stadium and a new hospital in
Zambia,
but that doesn't make them saints in the
eyes of the people who live here.
A typical monthly wage packet is around
54 pounds, the minimum wage in Zambia.
Hardly enough to feed a family.
It's not that the Chinese underpay.
It's just that they pay Chinese wages
[music]
for Chinese working hours.
And that has unnerving implications for
everyone who wants to win Chinese
investment.
The lesson from Zambia seems clear. If
you want the Chinese to invest in your
economy, and we seem to want that to
happen here, then you'd better be
prepared to work Chinese hours for
Chinese pay.
Now, you may say that doesn't apply to
us. They're impoverished Africa and
we're the developed West.
We're meant to be the smart ones, aren't
we? With the bright ideas.
The Chinese just screwdriver things
together for us.
But then you find that the Chinese are
doing what we think of as our job.
They're innovating, too.
Welcome to the Zhongguancun District of
Beijing, China's Silicon Valley.
>> [music]
>> Back in the 1980s, it was just a small
street where electrical goods were sold.
Now it's home to some of the world's
biggest laboratories for research and
development in electronics.
Lenovo was founded 25 years ago with
just 50 employees.
Today, after its takeover of the mighty
IBM's personal computer business, it's
the second biggest PC manufacturer in
the world.
>> One of the myths, I think, about China
today is that it's
>> You may think that the cutting-edge,
high-tech gadgets we use are all
designed in the West and merely
assembled in China.
He Yangqing is Lenovo's chief
technological officer in charge of R&D.
And he has news for you.
>> The fifth of humanity is your market,
yeah, and that is China. Then, pretty
quickly, innovations that happen here
will become global [music] standards.
>> Of course, I will show you a demo. It's
we call her hybrid system.
>> Oh, I see.
>> This is a Lenovo laptop.
>> So you can just slot it in and out, and
it's a laptop
screen and a touch pad. I have to admit
that is pretty cool.
>> Yeah.
>> So the idea that China doesn't innovate
is just completely wrong.
>> That's wrong.
I I disagree.
>> Yeah.
>> In fact, in the past 15 years, the
number of new patents granted to Chinese
innovators has increased by a factor of
29.
Overtaking Britain, Russia, France, and
now even Germany in the process.
China has built the world's fastest
passenger train timed at 300 miles an
hour.
And even as the American space program
gets cut back,
China is expanding hers.
Both are symbols of a profound shift in
global power.
China's reached a critical juncture in
its economic development. The days when
things were all designed in California,
but assembled in China, are surely over.
In fact, I can imagine a future in which
they're designed in China, but assembled
in California.
The implications of this shift are huge.
For hundreds of years, the West got rich
by having the technological edge over
the rest of the world.
But that era is ending.
Increasingly, it's we who are becoming
dependent on China's economic dynamism.
Amazingly, no fewer than half the
apartments in that Canary Wharf
development are owned by Chinese
investors.
And that symbolizes the reality that
China is now the West's single biggest
creditor.
The Chinese own a huge chunk of the US
government debt, they have more than two
trillion dollars in international
reserves. No wonder the Europeans went
cap in hand to Beijing when they needed
somebody to bail out the Euro.
>> [music]
>> So, we'd better get used to living with
China as a new economic superpower in
our lives.
But that may mean working longer hours
for less money.
Yet if that seems alarming, just
consider the alternative.
Suppose China's economy failed.
That would mean no Chinese investment in
our ailing economies.
No more Chinese spending on Western
brands.
And no one to buy the West's soaring
government debt.
Worse, an economic slowdown might also
unleash forces inside China
that are far more threatening than
anything we've yet encountered.
One of the comforting stories we tell
ourselves is that as the Chinese become
richer, they'll become more like us
and will ultimately adopt our values.
But I'm not sure it's going to be quite
like that.
I don't detect much popular appetite for
Western-style democracy in China.
What I do detect
is a growing Chinese nationalism.
>> I got up at 4:00 this morning to come
and film the raising of the red flag in
Tiananmen Square.
Now, that's not my best time, but I
thought at least there wouldn't be too
many people here at such an early hour.
Didn't expect that about 1% of the
population of the People's Republic
would have got here first. This is
Chinese nationalism in action.
So, you've come all this way and got up
at 4:00 this morning to watch a flag
being raised.
>> They arrived here at 3:00 a.m.
>> 3:00?
You must be tired. And why is it so
important?
If you If you ran up the British flag at
4:00 in the morning, nobody would show
up.
Of national pride.
Thank you very much indeed. Thank you.
Well, he seemed nice enough.
But, there's a darker side to the
resurgent nationalism that has surfaced
in China, particularly among the young.
One way this manifests itself is in
shrill attacks on the way the Western
media represent China.
I first saw this video in 2008, which
was a momentous year for China. It was
the year of the Beijing Olympics, but it
was also the year of massive unrest in
Tibet. And the video is an incandescent
response to the Western media's
treatment of the Tibetan events. Well, I
was dying to know who made it, but I
just couldn't find out. 3 years later, I
found them.
>> Passionate. This group of young Chinese
nationalists set up an organization
called Anti-CNN.
Its aim was to give a pro-Chinese
version of the conflict between ethnic
Tibetans and Han Chinese.
>> What inspired you to to make this video?
>> Give our voice to the world.
>> You seem to be saying that China should
be more assertive and should make its
position
clearer in a more forthright way.
>> Sometimes we should
be more assertive.
>> Yeah.
>> To give our voice. Right is right. Wrong
is wrong. Not so not so. Our government
is too weak, we think.
>> Right.
>> Sometimes sometimes
>> Your government's too weak.
>> Sometimes only.
>> Their claims about Western media bias
may seem bizarre to us.
But just think about what they said.
This new generation of Chinese
nationalists think their own government,
the people who gave us Tiananmen Square
and the crackdown in Tibet, is too weak.
It's a good illustration of the newly
assertive mood among many young Chinese.
And some of them have passed the stage
of just making videos to express their
feelings.
They already regard themselves as being
at war with the West.
But this is a uniquely 21st century form
of war.
>> Now, you may think that the strategic
front line of the Chinese-American
rivalry is somewhere in the South China
Sea or the Taiwan Strait, but you're
wrong. It's right here in the cyber
cafes of the back streets of Beijing.
>> Liu Cheng is a hacker,
a Chinese computer hacker and founder of
the Red Hacker Alliance.
Mr. Liu sees his patriotic mission as
defending Chinese interests against
attacks from the West.
But the best form of defense
is often attack.
According to MI5, Chinese hackers have
infiltrated the computers of British
defense,
energy,
telecommunications and manufacturing
companies
to steal their intellectual property.
Our intelligence agencies have also
monitored thousands of attacks aiming to
access restricted information on
government computers, including those of
the Ministry of Defense and the Foreign
Office.
Liu Cheng may not have been responsible
for these attacks on Britain,
but there's no doubt he personifies a
new kind of online warrior.
>> In the West, a hacker is usually seen as
a as a criminal. So, how can you be a a
nationalist hacker? Can you explain that
to me?
But, isn't that illegal?
Is there a cyber war going on now
between China and the United States?
>> This is not a video game.
The US government has stated that
computer sabotage coming from another
country can constitute an act of war.
>> So, will China be our economic savior
or our geopolitical nemesis?
There's no use pretending the answer
doesn't matter to you.
It makes a big difference if a fifth of
humanity decides to hack you rather than
to hire you.
So, which will it be?
Well, I believe history offers a clue.
>> China is bound to grow. It's also bound
to grow more slowly. It's internal
problems, demographic, environmental,
and social are serious. They're not so
serious that they can't be coped with
with a combination of overseas
expansion, export, investment, and
immigration, and technological
innovation.
The real worry is that in order to deal
with these problems, and to stave off
any pressure for democratization,
China's leaders may be tempted to
exploit that strong mood of patriotic
fervor that is such a striking feature
of China today.
>> This is the nightmare scenario.
China's economy falters.
Unrest breaks out.
And the specter of Dong Luang turmoil
returns.
To appease popular anger, the Chinese
government panders to a resurgent
nationalism.
It blames the West for its problems,
and becomes increasingly aggressive
towards us.
Far-fetched?
Not really.
It wouldn't be the first time in history
that a rising power has pursued an
aggressive foreign policy to stave off
pressure for domestic political reform.
Rapid growth,
internal instability,
youthful nationalism,
overseas expansion.
We've seen it all before.
I for one am vividly reminded of the way
that Germany made its first bid for
world power a hundred years ago.
A bid that led ultimately to the First
World War.
>> So, China really is the biggest question
of our time.
Could its rise repeat the same
disastrous trajectory of Germany a
hundred years ago? Or can we somehow
manage the transition from west to east
in a way that is peaceful, not violent?
Well, on the answer to that question
depends not just the prosperity of the
world, but its future peace.